All right you guys hear me okay cool I know everybody's going to kind of trickle in
...the after lunch session that's fine I appreciate you guys coming on the last day
is great did everybody go see a of...last night, yeah?
That's good right james baiter just makes everything cool I can pretty much watch anything he's in so,
thanks...common on the last a...really appreciate your time my name's thomas
...program manager in windows in the notifications team and I have andrew bars of me and...to
be doing demos for us today so, let's just jump right and we got quite a bit of content.
Before I get started evaluationswe are definitely highly competitive
in my team and there's a developer who did a presentation from our team this year...a
...a natural rivalry so I really need to be them I need
a better score than john sheehan got so please evaluate if you like the session afterwards and if you didn't like it is known to it.
...a quick intro about where you're at right now so if you've gone to some of the app model
sessions the application model session throughout this present...throughout the conference so far
...seen some of this stuff I mean robber just finished his session on a kind of how apps...work your
in our session now about shell really about how you integrator application with a lot of shel features and we're going to
talk about toasts tiles notifications in general so that's just a quick layer the land of all the
other things you should go look at if you haven't seen them yet about the app model and integrating
...windows ten.
So, I'm really excited about this year because this
...actually very different from me this is my fourth year...build and every year when I'm up here on...at the
costly think to myself don't talk about that new stuff that you're doing...talk about that
stuff you did six months ago and keep the new stuff out of your presentation and this is the first
year we're not doing that I'm talking to about what we're working on right now as a matter-of-fact
it's so bleeding edge that andrew may have a few glitches and
his demo because it's from a custom build that we have just so we can show you the latest and greatest
stuff just bear with us if it's not exactly perfect but for the most part we think it's all going to work out for
you and that's great because I've never had a chance to tell you about the now
...the future at this conference that makes me really,
really happy so what we heard from last year I just want to recap what
developers told us after we finish build last year...they said they want
...the coming year last year when the big piece of feedback I got was that there's not
programmers anymore okay people are now
...programmers so I wanted to take that piece of feedback and immediately update that part of the slide?
This powerpoint icon came with the
...cycle like I didn't have to go find the unit cycle it was included as part of this
guy and now seriously what we heard was...like what you're doing with convergence but we want to
see more unity more convergence about windows apps so we're going to talk about that today you've heard a lot
about the universal windows platform and universal windows apps today we're going to tell you a little bit more about how our stuff
it's ended...you said how could you maybe, you know,
converge...you...to hire edit and she has the same company you have a phone you have things that
are happening on desktop they don't really look like they're the same family so we're going to talk about some ui convergence as well
and the notification space you said well thanksgiving as a notification
center and action center as we call it and phone why is it in desktop ones that can
happen so you've seen some of the flight some of the preview releases that we've had there are there is an action
...continuing to evolve and it's continuing to get closer and closer between the phone and a desktop
...I'll show you some more about where that's going...said please don't say more templates if the
notifications spaces new...might not realizes but for those of you that have been doing windows tile and windows
toast notifications for a while you might know about the template catalog we...eighty-something templates
in a template cataloging very many people told me last year that flexibility is not more
and more and more templates please don't come back next year and tell me that you gave me more templates so we'll talk
about that too and finally more powerful notifications can do more with these can I make
the more interactive so that my customer can do stuff faster so we're going to get into that as well today
so we're done today...addressed all these...points the developers gave us from last year so first
of the theme of the conference...universal windows apps what does it mean in our case what
it actually means is that we were mostly done with the
binary convergence the platform last year so we actually had pretty much everything unify
...binary level when we talk to build last year but all the api...now fully
converged as well so basically if you look at the api surface for notifications at the end of windows
phone eight one that's what's available now to any universal windows out it's a fully converge
...all there that means things like managing your toes and action center all of that exists for you...
On top of that it's going to work everywhere on the windows device families so pc's mobile xbox I
ot...all again part of the universal windows platform and that's great because just right
...that are code for all these powerful things you can do a notifications now.
So, let's move on to talk a little bit about how the
y is changing and evolving and what this the principles for when we did that look
like very quickly starting tiles...about a couple of really,
really key things thousand need to be glanceable your
consuming information from tiles or something that's...quickly learn about what's going on
...application it's you're really kind of most obvious way to connect with your customer because
they're always on start so they need some way to quickly consume that information before they even...so it's all
about glance ability it's also about of course actually launching the app wouldn't be any good if they couldn't get
into it so just like every other platform out there have to have some way to launch into the apps that's another really
key principle about start...tiles...for how you actually take actions to get inside the
app the doorway into your app it's the way the user gets in so let's see what
actually looks like in practice in that case so I'm going to talk to a little bit about
start the layout of tiles I'm going to do some things about talking about density because when you think about the
family of devices that we have now from all the way down from mobile really small devices to
pc's to huge devices like surface hub there's a lot of screen densities
available now so we talk about our tiles and kind of this grid it'snot a real pixel
...obviously it's kind of relative pixel grid for us but how sizes break down into a pixel grid for us
and starts with the smallest tile if you look at number one up on the screen that's the
small tile for us that's a one by one tile we have the
medium tile two-by-two we have the wide tile which is four by two and then we also still
have the large tile and the large tile is still desktop only that's not going to be an mobile for now and,
it's a four-by-four so essentially this is the
basis for everything that we do going forward and for how we think about screen density and being able to
...those things on all the different devices that we have so, for example,
tiles are not always going to be the same-size because of that this is an example of
a high-density screen you can think of this is something like a leukemia fifteen twenty something that has a
really nice display on you can fit a lot of tiles on the screen
but we also have devices out there that are more like a loomis six thirty five and this may be the
...density that they're able to display and you can see that I'll go back and forth there
are definitely a different density so...different amounts of information that you can fit
on these tiles the adapt to the screen there on the
...are actually scaling depending on the density of the screen we've done some other stuff like reducing
margins to make all this work a little better but this doesn't just apply to mobile I know
...used phones examples but it applies to desktops and applies to anything with
...screen density that can change so a lot of what we did this time around was to make sure we...adapt
...densities and just give you the best-looking tile no
matter what devices actually running on so with that let's talk about the tiles...the
...that you can use as a developer yourself like I said there is a legacy template
catalog out there today it's eighty plus templates out
there and we did get the feed that back that the templates are okay but we don't really just want more
template so that's we addressed most of our work was not just enhancing additional templates but I just
want-to let-you know that all the legacy temples are just going to continue to work there's nothing that stopping those temples
working they actually look even better they've been given some visual ui refresh as well whenever they are
shown on windows ten so you can keep using all that stuff if you're already using it today you don't actually have
to change however we are doing something new called adaptive tile
templates so this is a template that does not need...
is instead of having multiple templates this is really just a set of for templates for small medium
widen large tiles that are incredibly flexible you can
do really great stuff inside these templates to layout your content your images so
that looks really great and create a lot of scenarios without having to just use a background image or
without using a static template so you get a lot more flexibility and we're going to
talk now about what that all looks like and how you do it so
introducing adaptive our templates hopefully the feedback this...for build won't be any more
...because...only really for that
...the real principle here is that the contents will adapt with the tile
nine notice looks like a small medium and large tile but
it's not this is the same tile and it's changing depending on the density
the screen it's running on can display so on
the far-left that is a very low density screen you can see it's not actually able to display
that much content...some content but not as much as when you move to like something like a
medium density screen in the middle or even a large density screen on the right remember
that's still all medium tile but on a high-density screen because you can put so much
more information inside there we can actually display more information and we wanted to take advantage of that
so let me show you how you would actually achieve that we still use xml for
our templates so we're still have a basic xml
layout that you use and there's a couple of key things to point out here to make this actual
situation work so if you look at the groups and the subgroups that I've got here?
Groups are about semantically binding information together so,
for example, in this email case john those email and...the first couple lines from john
...email makes sense to be displayed together as
a group you want your user to see all of that content together because it just gets a better experience
and jane those email...the same kind of thing you'd really want to have all of her email content
shown together you notice that on the small and the medium tile gino's email isn't
shown at all and that's because it's in a different group you said to us as
a developer semantically this information needs to sit together so only display if you
can display everything inside this group so that's why as we move up
the densities we get to a point where that medium tile has enough density to show all the information
include the additional group so that's where the adaptive nys of the tower
really takes advantage of what you want to send as a developer to give the best possible experience
...all devices I want to give kind of another example of this as well.
This is a pretty simple example about re flowing text on the medium-size
tile you can actually see quite all of the text in the string on the sm tile
on the medium-size of the medium tell you can on the most dense part of
the medium tile you can see the entire string and the way I've done that
is actually pretty simply if you look in the xml for text hint
...equals true I've just said...this text whenever you can and all of the tiles of
...the medium tiles is tried to...the...just that on the lowest
density screen there wasn't a way to fit quite all of it but on the highest density screen on the
medium tile I was able to fit all of...so we displayed all of it on the...we get to the demos a little bit later and
is going to show you some really cool stuff...this is going to show you some much more advanced examples but I just wanted
...t up some of the conversations that he's going to be having a little bit?
One of the talk a little bit about the state of tiles to so there's three
basic states of adaptive tiles and really this first state is just your tile as it
exists whenever you're app is first install so you the sm tile as a medium
tiles a wide town a large thailand this example they're all just using assets that came directly from
your package so this is just without any tile updates yet what
your tile would look like with the user tended to start and resize that this
is a simplest state your tile can be in this before you really done anything to it from a notification respect.
We have a semi live state this is really when you're trying to communicate
...small amount of information to the user makes sense or something like account you want to update the
count on the tile the badge...information for your user and it's, you know,
just a very quick way for the user glance and see that something's changed inside
your application the next state of courses the one that most people use and that's the live state
of the tile again I've got the template names up...to see tile small tom medium
...wide and tile large that's all you need from now on if you want to use the adaptive
how templates all we've got we don't have any new anymore templates other than those
for...showing a lot of text examples but it's going to get a lot more interesting in a minute so,
the live state is a state where you have more content showing is not just a badge now
your to doing some text on the tau you maybe doing some images...can I show you what that
looks like another view I just have a slide that kind of breaks it down.
Into the layers that exist so again in the basic state of the tile this
is before you've done anything to it you have the following layers have the plate which is really just a fancy word
...the background color you have an apple logo so this is out of your manifest the
square one fifty by one fifty logo that you have then you have the short name this is really just
the name that you've given your app in the manifest again this is when you've done nothing to your tile these are the
layers that exist and what this how the system build them up to show your tile and
the semi live state really only one layers added and that's the badge that gets added over the top
...the bottom right corner you see it is the top layer and that stacking of layers
again nothing else about the tile has really changed is your square one fifty by one fifty logo
in the middle the badges now and the bottom righted still using your logo for the or sorry
...short name from the app because all you really done is update the badge count this example?
And, finally in the live state is where a whole new layers introduced
that gets really interesting so if you look now the second layer from the bottom is now
your content layer this is where you can do things like images you can do
tax you can do great new stuff that's going to show you on the next slide this is really where
you insert the stuff that you...light your user with information and really bring your tile to life
...this content layer so let's move on to talk about the content
...content notifications can display and image like I said
...combination of those things sometimes inline...not sometimes the full background I
wanted to give you some examples of real tiles that are being built for our internal
...microsoft apps that are actually being built and shipping in the
stores part of windows ten and what they did and how they're tiles are going to look using this actual
adaptive...so we'll start with the one that we've been showing so far is the mail tile
...just text on a tile because that makes more sense...you want to
see what's going on in reality if you had something like...attach...attachment and
email they could be showing that on the...well if they want as an inline image but for this simple example
just showing the ...from and...the first-line of the mail,
for example,...next one is actually from the calendar app so this is
text just basically on the tile pretty simple again but it's on a wide tile
and this case is just got more information on it because it's a wide tyler stretches a little wider here's something a
little more complex so this is what a whether tile could do so this one
...inline image and some text grouping are able achieve all of this with the adaptive mark-up and
...actually going to take you through this one and just a little bit?
You've got some pretty simple examples the music app could just use a background image in this case...using
album art...background image and it could just put the name of the album and
the name of the...on the front that once...background image which sometimes you
...a full bleed image all the way across the back and just...some text on the front
...your even able to control the overlay as well so if you wanted to have the
image kind of be darkened a little bit to make text display a little better you can do that as well.
And, finally the last example something like the xbox
tile this is what something very similar with the games app is actually going to ship and this is an inline image
and text and kind of in some columns and again all done with the adaptive layouts got
an image I've got some bigger text of the top a couple of lines of subtle text underneath it created with the adaptive
...so now I want to actually flip over to andru so that he can do the demo and show
you how all this works in the real-world...code on what is hopefully stable...
as...talked about these adaptive tiles let-you create really powerful tiles really easily so
what we're using here that you can see it's called
...template visualize are going to ship a tool like this for you guys that you can play around
with the tiled templates really quickly and we're going to do is we're going to walk through how you
would actually start design your live tile so over on the right we have
our default app state as you can see there and we're going to start by sending
a tile payload here and basically it's all xml as you saw with
...examples and you have a tile and visual element and then you have your
bindings for each size we're just going to start by working on the medium tile
says you can see over on the right there the medium tile is blank
renounced we have no...so we can add some text.
Hello, san francisco.
And, you'll see that appear over on the medium tile and we can add another line attacks
is basically a stack panel welcome to build two thousand fifteen.
And, we got to lines attacks going there so that works really well but we
...many make it look a little better so we can add some styles.
Hint style body that'll make the tax...bit bigger as
...hello san-francisco got bigger and the second-line we won that the
...so we can say hint...
And, now we have rapping tax and we can also add a style to that.
Of captions subtle.
To great out a little bit.
I do that because
...kind of run yet into the icon epsy got full control of your apps branding you can
choose logo only you can have the name and logo or just the name and on
at medium tile we don't have much space
will just display the apps logo and now we want to design our wide
...tiles we can use basically the same code here so I'm just going to copy
paced and then add a tile why'd template
there and as you can see it works pretty well the tax expands to
the valuable size and we can include the apps name...we have...more
space on the tile and then we'll do the same thing for our large tile.
And, there we go we designer tile looks good so
redundant the design side now we can actually throw this into our app and you can
get content on your tiles a variety of ways we just built a little simple
...where we can paste in the xml and I'll turn it into
a tile so right now we have three tiles pinned here and I pasted in
our code that we just wrote and we'll update those tiles and you'll see those new
content appear on the actual start screen so really easy to create beautiful looking
...tiles one thing I want to point out there with that those three tiles
...on start now those got pinned at the same time if you've been a windows,
windows phone developer for a little while you might have in the tile and had to go back and...another tile you
...multiple tiles at...now you can multiple thousand once the start screen if you want
...because we heard a lot of feedback that was a pain people navigate
...the app on phone some people even thought the apples crashing when your navigated out of it
the start screen so now you can...multiple tile because it's about.
Yep, and,
in...demo he talked about the mel tile so...how you actually create that
mail tile and if we look at the wide
tile here you can see the content for wide has those two groups and
group semantically mean that the content passed a fit completely for to actually
make sense so since steve
...on the wide tile can't fit it doesn't appear but on the large tile which is the
exact same content just on the large it fits
we display it and then the weather tile which was the...has a lot of fancy
stuff going on if we look here we're on the tile why'd.
You can place and image in the background by saying placement background and then you can do
those subgroups which are columns and that's how we achieve over on the wide tile
those four columns and we can actually delete one of these subgroups here and you'll
see all go down to three columns so you have a lot of our and control you can set
weights on the columns do a lot of fancy stuff and also those images you can set them to
be placement inline and that's how you achieve those placements there so on the theme
...wanted to create a hips
...app called hips to me that I'll tell you where the newest hips
...showed up so we design this live tile and this guy's been spotted down on
...shows little map on the large tile since we got
a lot of space there and we have this tile designed here and we can do the
same thing copied over into our windows ten app here and update
...live tile and you'll see that content appear on our start screen here.
And, then the other way there's a lot of ways to get content your live tiles
...doing local updates there but there's also periodic polling which
would probably use that helps to app and basically with periodic
polling you have a website here and we would have a web server that generates
that tile xml content and then all the tile does is it periodically
polls that url the pull down the new content and update your
live tile so if we look at the code behind for that all we do to create
a polling tile is we create the tile and we
...it and as thomas said it doesn't throw you back out to start so you can instantly
do code after that and right here is that code where you actually
set the periodic tile the...down from your url I which is over here and we can go
over to our uw p and.
...that tile so.
Here we go will click pan and now be added to our start screen hopefully if the internet plays with
us yep and it pulled down that...we got our live tile.
The back to...okay thanks andrew.
hopefully you see that there's a lot of flexibility and what we did with the adapted templates we
really took the feedback the heart that you want to be able to late things out...a simple...effective way
so that's why we've done this technology it's pretty straightforward but there's also some powerful stuff we've
seen people doing internally and we hope to see what you guys do it we think it's going to be a fantastic addition to
your apps I wanted to talk a little bit about the api as we didn't talk about because there are a lot of
api the notifications...space and we're not going to cover them all today but really
there all the same as what they were before...say at the end of windows phone...wanted to go local was
in these namespaces the same one still available to interviewed
...and windows out you...notifications which is where you really do things
...thailand posts that's badge update manager
schedule tile notification tile of the manager and windows
...start screen is where you do secondary tiles all that stuff is still there...still
exists is just going to work exactly like it used to work if you're using that code or even if you have to become
new to this code that's fine whatever's on msdn today is exactly what's going to be supported in your
So, I also wanted to touch a little bit on how we send tile updates because andrew
and I showed you local and polling but there's multiple ways that you can send tile updates
your app so local is basically your immediate update scenario you can do it for
the foreground you can do it from the background local tile updates never expire tiles
have a concept of expiration especially when they're done something like a push server but we do a
local tile update they don't ever expire because we assume that you're going to come back and clean-up your content at some
point to a background task or something you have control over that if you want new content to show.
You also have schedule tile updates so scheduled
...is really exactly what it sounds like a specific date and time I want this tile to
change and those expire after three days because they appear to be time-sensitive in the first-place
so you can do a schedule pick a specific time tile...the schedules how you get to this guy.
What andrew showed so,
periodic is really about having the tile update on a kind of a regular occurrence you have
a uri you have some time period that you want update on over and over again because the xml
in the cloud is regenerated on a frequent basis and this is where
...content comes from so start periodic updated how you get to that guy
then finally something we're not actually talking about very much today is push notifications that you do tile updates
as well and everything that we're showing you today all the xml all these features they all work
to push notifications as well so if you can do it with the xml you...the push server
...just work it's a really great way to
do real-time information push notifications expire after three days again because
we're kind of time-sensitive it's one of the most popular ways to send a notifications so you can directly
...notification...there's also raw notifications so...to talk a lot about tiles
and toast today but a raw push notification is a really powerful thing available
on the pap platform...less you send basically...of shoulder
...to wake-up your background task and then you can do whatever you want...actually see a lot of apps move
into a model where instead of sending a tyler toast notification specifically to the
push server this into raw wake-up their background task and then do something from
that background tasked update...thaler properties and it seems to be a pretty powerful model because you have a local
...of local client state you can use in those scenarios to give the most relevant notification to the user?
And, I want to talk a little bit about beyond adapted tiles as well because like I said we're talking to
about stuff it's not just from right now it's from coming soon as well so this is my
...this my breaking into jail slide because I feel like I'm going to get these questions at the end of the talk anyway so I
want to just kind of get this stuff out there one greatly thing that's coming that's going to be really
helpful is something called example rendering background task now this existed in windows phone
eight one but it's never existed in desktop...now exist for anything that's a universal windows
app essentially it's a way for you to create content you can take and create
...controls and stuff in visual that you
like and then render it to an actual image that you then for the whole image on your tile
so whenever adaptive doesn't quite meet your needs you need to do something a little more advanced or something we have
enabled for-you you-can...rendering background
task just render an image and make a kollek awesome that way it's available now to all universal windows...
I know I'm going to get this question so I'm going-to go ahead and talk about it you're showing
...xml it seems relatively powerful...you just give us
example why is are not just them on the tiles and that's a great question and it's something that we
want to do we think there's two categories of developers and we've seen this and
other ecosystems as well there's developers want to spend...some amount of time other
tile they don't have an infinite budget we all know that sometimes we have a lot of money to spend on something
like a tile sometimes you only have a little if you just want to do something quick easy very effective
and very flexible...is perfect for that if you're
a really powerful them all developer and you're thinking yourself off I just had sample I can
do often storyboards I could do awesome animations we understand
that we're going to enable that as well as example tiles or something...actively working on and we're
going to bring that to the platform at some point in reality we're not actually there yet so we don't
have as example start screen on mobile we do on desktop if you didn't know
what the start menu on desktop is really just...same goes for notification to action center it's really just
...but we don't have...on mobile yet and we're working on it so we're actually limited by our own
technology in this case and we're going to make that change so that we can bring something like example tiles
developers who really want to spend the time to do it one other point I want to make that is sometimes
overlooked is that push notifications
are great but sending example down for a push notification
...really ugly like can you imagine all of...you need to create a really awesome tile
...deal with escaping and worrying about all that...this and it down for push notification
and I'm not even sure we would support some really big example because we only let you have four-k of total size
...payload so, flexible sorry adaptive templates are better for something
like push notifications they give you a lot of flexibility without so quite so much texan
...notification so that's important thing to take into consideration about why we do both
technologies and then finally...this question too what about interactive tiles,
come on, give me something where I can actually have like a button or some interaction on the tile itself and it's not
something we've got quite yet but is something that we actively explored...on my team has been exploring this
for this entire release we're looking at how we can make interactivity on tiles something really,
really awesome for developers and we have a lot of ideas that we're thinking about ways that you
...deeply from your tiles,
for example, so, I just wanted to throw out there that we haven't forgotten about these features we
know you guys want this stuff and we're going to work on it and find a way to bring...to you in the near future.
So, now let's shift gears a little bit we spent some time talking about tiles now let's talk
about post notifications and action center...talk about the ui updates first of all that
are coming with those two technologies just like tiles
action center and...have some principles that we tried to abide by
very similarly toaster about glancing information you consume new information from your
app real difference between posts and tiles is that toaster interrupt of
...still glanceable they're not a ton of information but they
happened to come to the user when the user may not be looking at the stars additionally
...are much more about actions they're much more about doing something to either launched
app or taken action
...app think is interesting I mean they by their nature they invite you to kind of create a complete
...task because they are interrupted so,
let's see a little bit of how that is actually going to work with a new action...windows ten across all
of the different skews we have been moving to the same look and feel for the windows family you hopefully
...notice that between the mobile builds and desktop builds action sensors are very similar
we're trying to be very thoughtful of where you interact these things, for example,
you notice on the desktop that you can invoke action center from the task bar you can...from swiping to the
...the right as well as a mobile you pull down from the top because we believe it makes sense
to have different interaction model depending on device type that you're using optimized keyboard mouse
versus optimized for touch in some cases most of the behaviors that exist and action center where to
...inherited directly from windows phone the stuff that's new that I'll talk about and blue but,
everything else
is the behavior that started in the windows phone timeframe so toast automatically
going to...center...existing windows app and you're using...notifications now after
they...displaying on the screen they go directly into actions center and then they
lived there until the user does something with them something new is that...can now be expanded to
view...content and this is great because it actually helps existing developers if your
phone developer today and use into...notification with a lot of content
inside of it we only show the first-line essentially now you can send that same
toast notification of windows ten device the user...pulled down the
...and see a lot more content so you have to changer app for that if you're already doing that
in sending a lot of content then you'll be able to just let the user get that new feature.
The you cannot chase individual notifications...negotiates individual notifications
...notification action center it launches the app whatever deep think that you had you
can clear all your always able to do that on phone you can remove for apple group which means there's a header
for your notifications...shows your app and
swipe the entire group away but now you can remove as a user individual notification
so if you've got five notifications from my app and I just my triage the first two I can do that and just
wipe them away and then we also have the ability for alarms and reminders to the viewed inside of
center now so if an alarm notification comes up I'm going to talk a little bit about the scenarios a
...to do that a little bit you can actually show hideout notification and it will show up inside
action center to take action on later if you want to ...some of the
...to show you can just make it go away right away as a developers up to you.
So, let's talk again about the basics of
...notifications just like we did about the basics of tile modifications.
First templates legacy templates are still there so there weren't quite as many
...temples...thousand-plus are only eight...templates they were kind of
the same thing though the first for...templates work text and different layouts and other for
...templates were images and different layouts so,...tell
samples will still work there is some good news if you notice before and windows phone if you use
them a toast template that had images and it wouldn't show the image it would work on
desktop...just not be shown on phone now if you send that notification to
phoned image will show up on windows ten device so there is some enhancements there will be able to use
toasted images in the legacy payloads if you want to...images will show up
...got that scenario but just like adaptive tiles were talking about adaptive
toast today as well but it's not just adaptability of the content in the toaster going to talk about it's
also interactivity so we have adaptive and interactive toast notifications
now and again the most flexible...template we ever had and there's only one template for
...post generic that's it and you can do all the things I'm going to show you
just that one template so for desktop
and mobile going to show you a couple different examples I want to start with this first one of
something like in qq you've gotten some new photos posted and there's to notify
...showing to an application for desktop and mobile but they're really the same exact notification
are...difference a little bit on desktop you'll see that there's no dragged to
expand notification because on desktops we've got the room they all come out
...expanded like this whereas on mobile users
...notification down so they can see more information because we just don't have that much room
on mobile here's another example of doing some interaction this is one we hope takes off we really think it will if
you've used the flights that we've got for the phone build you've seen this today where you can do a quick
reply to a message for the sms messaging out
and we think a lot of apps are going to adopt this is one of the most powerful ways to the user interact with your
app without them actually switching from what they're doing so in this case you can see we've got a quick apply message.
And, then another example this could be something like sap if you wanted to have a
couple quick buttons and you want to say ...actually for vacation...want accept or decline in my
...a...somebody like andru asking for vacation and I would definitely decline it because they just...doesn't need any time
So, this is some really simple examples but we're going to go on and talk about actually showing you some of these
and a little bit and how you can create them on your own so introducing this stuff you can do with adaptive
and interactive toasts so just like tiles the content
...the toasts there's more room we show more...less room we show less?
Here's an example ofbeing able to show more content is a really simple
xml example of what I'd used in inline image so I've got an image here I've got a couple
of lines of text and you'll notice just like in tiles for that image placement because inline
is for that larger image of the room but I've also
replaced the app icon that would normally show up in the top
left the toast with my own image and I did that using image placement equals apple logo
overwrite towards the top so we're really trying to let you have as much flexibility with this area as
we possibly can before things like that would only be the app icon now you can kind of
...and do your own thing?
Show another example of if you want to do something a little more complex of action this is a rendell of what
...to do their using our adaptive templates as well so they've actually shown
and image they've shown some text they shown a mapping here they've even got some selection boxes to
let-you snooze this and then they've got snooze and dismiss buttons
for what you want them to do with this notification and if you look we've got some things like activation
types as well I'm going to talk a little more about the activation types and a little bit and,...
actually show you that is one of demos too and what it means to handle when these buttons are clicks and how you deal with
...then I got one more quick example this is...example for highly do something like a quick
reply notifications so you can see really I've done here is in the action section about
...box that's as much as it really takes and, you can retrieve that input whenever
...you can do whatever you want to do with it and we've actually got a real live working example that for you a
little bit as well so three quick examples of what you can do with interactive notifications?
I...talk about the states of tows as well just like I did tiles so I talk a little bit about
already but the collapse state of a toasts is really what you see on mobile by default but
whenever you go into actions center because we want to show you more stuff once the...moved off the screen
...action center for the most part they're always collapsed and the user can expand them if they want
...here's an example of them being collapsed in the phone action center this is the same policy we...a desktop
action center because we want...show you more information about your notifications all together and
they're so we by default collapse them all up here's one more example of a
collapse notification before I've pulled down on those river to actually show more about
the notification then I talked about the expanded state now the expanded state
in this case...I've gone into actions...clicked on the notification the little down-arrow of
expanded notification out and you can see that everything I can do with the notification when it came to my
screen in the first-place I can do with it when it's action center they
...collapse but nothing changes about the notification depending on where it's at it's always going to go
to do all of its actions no matter where it ends up this is a similar example of a notification that's already
pre expanded on desktop like I said because we have more room on desktop we automatically pretty
expand some things.
And, then I want to talk a little bit about scenarios that can let you decide to
...expand notification as well so we do have scenarios for alarms now we think
of everything as a notification now there's not a separate alarms or reminders namespaces all
...notification and the scenario is what
decides the behavior of that notification so in this case
there's a whole bunch more xml I would have here but for the most part this scenario equals alarm inside of that
...is what actually tells me that I want this to be
bree expanded because whenever you're alarms wake you up at, you know,
let's say some reason all-time like eight o'clock then you just want to quickly hits
news for dismiss news in my case and not have to actually pull that notification down because
it's an alarm type of notification we wanted to give developers...to say go ahead and
...expands and something very similar applies for reminders again whenever
...reminder to go home comes up...you want to be traffic you don't have to pull
...down...to let you use this narrow reminder to actually pretty expand that notification
so shows up as big as it should be for the user.
We have one really interesting one we actually have an incoming call
scenario as well and depending on the skew I don't have example for...this is an example for
phone you can actually have a full-screen notification that lets you do something like an incoming call
...this case going to answer button a message button and ignore button and because calls
...critical to the mobile experience we've decided to rendered full-screen on desktop we
probably wouldn't...full-screen...might be bigger but it wouldn't take up your whole screen because it's not the primary function of the
devices...using the take a call necessarily and you just again specify this with the scenario
...scenario equals incoming call so you can do some really powerful stuff with
these scenarios to give your user the best experience with notifications.
So, the launch types so all of those things as buttons that you saw that you do a different launch type
for your application and the most obvious one is a foreground activation just like you've always been able to tap on the
toast itself to launch the app now you can tap on the button to launch the
...so in the foreground activation
...button the app launches...arguments that we passion to you...you do whatever
makes sense to your at this is kind of the simplest most straightforward thing that we had from before and now...but.
We have background activation
as well so any of those buttons could actually invoke a background task and actually
...that up to do some work for me in the case of doing something like a quick reply once the user interest in text and
hits that send button you're really going to wake up your background task go communicate with your server...have
your service and that message over to the next user so again you tap the button the task launches
your...some arguments that we give you...give you the input id we give you what was actually in the box
...give you all the stuff that the user touched on the toast and then you take actions on that
...make sense figure out there's two more types I want to talk
about this protocol activation as well this one's really important us were really,
really invested in like having a web of apps on your device and protocols
are perfect way to do that protocols are more than just something like http and
there's everybody's old favorite has been there forever mail to,
for example, you can do those you can also do...app communication this way I could launch the
being maps app actually anders...show you that a little bit so you tampa
button the protocol activates the system handles that and then whatever the activation was supposed to launch actually gets
launched can be a web page be and app is a really great way to do...half or up to website scenarios.
And, finally we have some system activation types so, for example,
I showed you could have a dismiss button that would wake up a background task and then you would handle that
dismissing your app or maybe I hits news...in your background task would reschedule
notification for a little later on if you don't want to deal with that if you don't want to have to write the coding
your background task to handle rescheduling notifications...the system do a
...as a couple of system activation types that really only apply to things like alarms
...reminders for things like snooze and dismiss we don't rightly code you to stay system activation
type equals alarm...reminder and then if you hit the user has this news button the
shell is taking care of making sure that notification pop back up you don't have to handle that your background task.
And, then there's one more thing I want to talk about before throat over to
the demo post notification history change trigger this one is really great
features so this trigger just like a lot of triggers in the system has a certain time
...fires and for us...is whenever...notification for your app
and action sensor has changed if I go into...on a swiping notification away
will launch this trigger which will...your background task and you can do whatever you want with that background
tasks a lot of people use this so that they can keep their tyler badge and saying
and I'm going to show you that...some people might use it to talk back to their cloud server as a matter-of-fact a good
use for this is if I've got the same app across multiple devices...I...all of
...devices and saying we got feedback and developers that
...they want to wait actually be able to achieve this so you use...history
change trigger whenever one notification get dismiss from my mobile device I could talk my cloud
...delete for that same notification with that same tagging group on another device and this
way you're in control of getting your notifications and...if you want so how do you
how do you do this well I'm not going to talk about it the better...could just show you so take it away.
...so, we're going to start off by creating a toast notification here.
So, here we're just constructing the...notification payload as you can see you put in your tile
and content in the adaptive part of it and then the cool stuff is the
actions down here so these are buttons those...text fields and those select
lists and as you can see you can do with those protocol activation like this one
launches being maps when we click this button you can much websites and you can launch
email clients and also background tasks and other things that
...talked about so we're going to issue that
...notification here in our...so here's the
...notification if I click near me are have semi...will show me hip
...that are near me by launching being maps and doing research for hip
...what find...economy's right
here that it's definitely a bug and then.
The things you can do you can launch wikipedia and find out about...
And, then you can also remove notifications as
thomas talked about so if we papa few notifications here.
And, we'll set a different tag for the second notification and now
have to notifications and here and you can pragmatically remove
...so we're going to
remove that top one by specifying the tag and we programmatic
...remove that is gone and you also have that
toast notification change trigger so if we look at our lives out here it knows we
have one notification in action center-right now if we go and
swipe that away we fire a background task and update
...tile...notifications so you can keep everything in
sync and provide a really good experience for your users.
Okay, I think that's cool but quake...quick reply is cool so
with quick reply we have a website here which finds out like what
...say and I just refresh it show you this is actually like live-in everything's running
on local host but otherwise it's alive and if we go to
our let's check out the code first basically we're going to issue a quick
reply notification and we're going to run this background task and in the background
task we take these...that we actually provide in
...notification and we pull out the message that user types and we send that to
our web server here and we just do http post
there so if we go back to our app we can send a
...for a quick reply and as you see it comes up here you can actually
...those in your action centered seo expand it and what
...hips or say well pbr...grab...and that triggered
our backgrounds task...if we go back to the website we can refresh and
see that you actually posted it from a background task?
Pretty cool stuff there and finally
thomas talked about scenarios for toasts this is another...payload here
and as you can see we have scenario alarm so in that appears if we
had audio working in the audio not working so audio and startling...
And, you can have the selection less there and here you can actually trigger background
tasks so our background task would go and trigger that notifications be
schedule ten minutes later back to...school thanks
...so we're almost the end that's most of what we've come to talk about today
...to recap windows dot you item notifications is where you get everything for tells
...what was there from
...still there today is your guys...you go used to do everything you need to.
And, I didn't talk much about push I talked a little bit about it but I just want to have it up here windows
...notifications all still there also exists great
...notifications and badges still...works great.
And, then one more thing I wanted to announce in the spirit of you know,
kind of more exclusivity of this conference I feel like our sell team that a really,
really amazing thing they went and made it possible
...thirty-two...to do adaptive...interactive this means.
This means classic windows apps...before project centennial this is right now and do
...essentially comic activation to bring their app up whenever
and interactive notification...now I don't have...time to...today
is a little bit complex but it works really well and we're going to have a sample upon msdn so
that people can use it and, I just, you know, I love to its for an awesome we actually used in the keynote them or?
Little bit of a recap so you said you want windows apps we hope we brought
you windows apps you said you want...ui updates you are refreshing
...everywhere now you see coming together notification central okay we did you action
...and windows we gave you adaptive thousand toasts instead of a
new template catalog and then finally more powerful notifications through interactive.
So, really enjoyed having...today...way to see what you do that we'll be putting the sample up
on msdn code gallagher possibly get bob will be putting the template visualize are up as well we hope
the community can contribute to...to do some awesome stuff or some examples of going to be fully open-source the temple
...you guys are going to go to see whatever you want with it and, just...great stuff we appreciate...
About ten minutes for questions so the microphone but.
Quick one so any plans on allowing any kind of sv deers
ammo based icons for those assets that we don't have to have like fifteen...
and resize them eighteen different ways okay so the question was can you give me something like
...high-profile so that I can or is even
...and the question is not you are the answers not is not quite yet but yes we realize that, you know,
something...that scale better is also a great addition to the software we just don't have
available for yet but, you know, what if you just keep giving the feedback...know hopefully
will go for you what we'd like to think...we're trying to do so it's really the only place we can't do it right you have
everywhere else in the app we can example...for everything, yeah, I totally agree from work?
With live tiles you have to set the ...color in the manifests is there anyway we
can have it...update to push a new background
colors to the live tiles.
The question was can-you pushed update the background color and it's really
...the closest...go to calmness...image and as the background
...a color and that roughly...same effect but you can't do it as part of it's not really part.
Fix-up imap method.
Right.
So, the tiles are great for having
user be able to watch monitors something in the background.
Tn when are we going to be able to allow them to put one on the desktop so they can
logic continuously okay so you're saying...wire my...available...desktop not just start
...fantastically the feedback as well I will absolutely talk to the
...about it I actually think that they did some exploration of it I'm not sure what their plans
are but where they have to find out you should...me...and...question.
Samoa.
...anybody else now.
Okay, go ahead you can see...
On sports.
So, the question really about restrictions of launching a background
...notification how often I do-it-yourself your examples every minute you could
absolute every minutethere is there is some restriction on the server-side of push if
you're incredibly high-volume notification provider we might
...throttle but we can work that out with the server team if there's some incredibly high-volume need to push for
real scenario and the problems to low we could figure out a way to make that better but if you I mean
that's scenarios great uone update your tile the latest sports scores you want to every minute
that will absolutely work now even mind the background tacit limited by the resources available
...so-if it's a five-fold meg phone that's currently in...and also
...of how my get update of the task...not run until some of the resources come back to assist but for the most
partner scenario there's, there's nothing really intentionally restricting in the...only resource.
The limits on the number of apps the can be registered for background notifications been relaxed the
...yes the question was that we remove...for the number of things that can be background like large background
tasks
yes I'm...henry will have the exact answer for that but I'm pretty sure that there's no limit.
...what happens to remainders of the for the acid
...using simulated gopal naps of us in the like a
tasks on phone if they're raising remainders but this be shown in the actions
and all when...been that mine that's a really good question so the question is if you're silverlight eight one
...using the alarming reminder instead of notification...they go and
actions and not right now currently they don't all the things that are actually part of the new
notification...access center because not everything mapped
...and we didn't want to change that experience on top of the user
in the developer so if you switch to something like an actual notification then you'll be able to have an
actions...mobile otherwise it won't on desktop...
alarming reminder notifications as well you might remember some apps actually on desktop implemented a
few buttons and those before those will go into actions and they're closer to the right framework on the right
action so they will go in access and even update them to look and feel like the new ones what's really
only silverlight on phone that doesn't change behavior...longer...focus great...
All right...be around so-if you...talk more ask more questions feel free come up we can go off
a insiders loans and thanks-again.